Nathaniel Cain

☑ nathaniel2897@gmail.com

github.com/yunglaundromat

in linkedin.com/in/nathaniel-cain

SKILLS

Languages:

Javascript, Ruby, Java

Frameworks:

React.js, Redux, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Selenium

Databases:

SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL

Additional:

Authentication/authorization using JWT and BCrypt

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development Graduated June 2019

City College of New York

Earned credits towards Bachelor's Degree in Political Science September 2015 - June 2017

Bard College

Associate of Arts
Graduated June 2015

ABOUT ME

Full stack web developer with a passion for urban exploration, political science, rock climbing and cartography. With thorough experience in Rails, JavaScript, and React.js and a background in sales and team leadership, I thrive in an environment of collaboration and respect.

PROJECTS

CityZen

Social media interface for NYC resident users to petition issues with transportation-related concerns. Uses authentication/authorization with JWT and BCrypt to give every user a login. Utilizes Leaflet to plot coordinates of each petition on a map. Ruby on Rails backend.

CryptoTrader

Collaborative project; a cryptocurrency purchasing simulator that reflects real-time values of cryptocurrency. Uses React.js client-side and Ruby on Rails server-side. Fetches data to the frontend using Coinranking API, which updates every few minutes with new data on coin values. Persists purchase data to the local backend.

BikeShare International

Collaborative project; an app to assist users looking to find bike share stations in cities across the world. Fetches data of every bike share system internationally from City Bikes API, giving users information on station location, free spaces, and bikes available. Persists "favorited" systems by user to server-side using Rails.

EXPERIENCE

Infosys

Junior Operations Associate

March 2020 – present Remote

- Trained on a variety of technologies, including basic Java, Selenium, and Unix scripting.
- Interviewed directly with clients of large-scale applications utilizing Selenium with Java.

Brooklyn BouldersCommunity Specialist

Sep 2016 – Aug 2018 Brooklyn, NY

- Greeted and assisted community members in front-desk check-in and Facility Orientations in a busy, fast-paced climbing gym.
- Consistently met and exceeded weekly and monthly sales goals, and completed thorough training sessions on crucial customer service skills.

Brooklyn Farmacy & Soda FountainGrill Chef Lead

Apr 2015 – Sep 2016 Brooklyn, NY

 Worked a variety of positions, including front-of-counter, server, and host, while contributing to a highly-profitable, fast-paced restaurant environment.